A NETFLIX ORIGINAL SERIES
STOP FRAUD
TRAITORS
They're attacking the bank.
Seal off the building!
I repeat, seal off the building!
Red protocol, sealing the doors.
I repeat,
we're sealing the bank doors.
Everyone, put on your vests.
All of you!
And then the Bank of Spain will be sealed.
Even when sealed off,
the building is very big, Professor.
Too many windows, not enough men.
We can't defend the whole thing.
Good point, Helsinki.
A really good point, but...
this building...
has its own secrets.
This is the part of the Bank of Spain
that interests us.
The structure is covered
with concrete walls
and steel sheets 180 centimeters thick.
From the outside,
it is a true safe.
From the inside,
it's an impenetrable fort.
Once red protocol is activated,
nobody, and I mean nobody,
will be allowed to go in or out
for one hour.
That's the time we need
to obtain a key piece
for stage two of our plan.
What piece?
The Governor of the Bank of Spain.
He'll be in his office,
escorted by five personal bodyguards
with a poor sense of humor.
I call that the ghost train.
Everyone knows
something weird is going on
and things will jump out,
but no one really knows from where.
Governor, sir, I'm Lieutenant Lorenzo.
You must come with us.
We need to evacuate you immediately.
Thank you, Amanda.
For now, I'm not leaving my office.
Sir.
It's a direct order
from General Salas Núñez.
-It comes from above.
-I received it,
but I'm not following it.
I'm not leaving the Bank until
the last employee has left.
So, if you want to protect me,
you'll have to sit down and wait.
Coffee, anyone?
Amanda, if you please.
Come in, come in.
At that moment,
I wondered what Nairobi might be thinking.
I only had one thought my mind:
to draw my gun
and rain hell down on them.
Get some rest.
Take a seat.
May I ask what regiment you belong to?
We're airborne sappers
from BRIPAC,
sixth brigade.
With demining missions in Mali, Lebanon,
Afghanistan.
There were five bodyguards.
We had two guns each,
so we could each take out two men.
It was still one too many.
Very risky business.
By the way,
how do you deactivate
an anti-personnel mine?
It depends.
There are many types of mines
and each one has a different mechanism.
There are the Green Parrots,
the Butterfly, the PMF1...
Some are activated by methods
that would defuse others.
Some explode due to movement.
Some...
explode when being opened.
Some even explode
when you get too close to them.
May I go to the toilet?
By all means. You can use mine.
Excuse me.
Amanda, if you please.
This way.
The worst are the Russian.
The Professor had prepared us
for any event.
But let's be honest.
Theory is one thing.
The actual action, another.
Go!
Move!
You'll be safe here.
Nothing to worry about
among writers and poets.
Stay calm.
Hands in the air.
Like this. Like in a robbery.
Come on.
Very good.
Ladies and gentlemen,
my name is Palermo.
And I have two pieces of news for you.
Good and bad.
The bad one is that the Bank of Spain
is under attack.
The good one...
We are the attackers!
Keep calm! Keep calm!
Keep calm!
Everyone, keep calm!
VP13.
VP13?
They have an electronic fuse
controlled by a seismic sensor.
Touch them...
and you're fucked.
Afghanistan was full of them.
I see you're well trained.
Sir, do not move.
Are you OK, Lieutenant?
Lieutenant!
Governor, sir...
Now you must come with us.
Get up.
Come with me.
What are you doing?
Don't move.
Guns down!
Don't move!
Well...
This doesn't look good for either of us.
Let's call it quits.
Quits? You think
we've reached a draw?
You won't shoot the governor,
but I'll do this bitch in.
I'll do it.
Gandía!
Release the girl.
Calm down, Amanda.
It's okay.
-Gandía, release the girl.
-No.
I don't want anyone harmed.
That is an order.
Gandía, release the girl!
I'm going with them.
And I don't want you to do anything.
That's right.
I don't know what you want,
but there's no way out.
Then we stay.
Fire!
Shit!
What the fuck!
What just happened?
-Shit! Okay...
-What are you doing?
They're going down. We need to go up.
-We're going down.
-Going down?
If we stay here, they shoot us.
Better to get out.
Let's gate-crash it, Tokyo style.
Shit's about to hit the fan.
Now you belong
to our wonderful hostage family.
We'll enjoy some days
of complete disconnection.
Take the masks and put them on, please.
Put the fucking masks on!
So that nobody feels inclined
to be a hero,
hand in your mobile phones
to my mate, Denver.
Let's do it this way.
Raise your hands if you're parents.
Okay.
We'll tag your mobile phones in red,
so you can make one phone call a day.
Where's that coming from, moron?
Because I say so
and I'm the hostage coordinator.
Did you take a course?
Are you daddy of the year?
Hand in your mobile phones now!
What about this white strawberry?
Oh, my God! You're such a snob, Tokyo!
He's such a cutie.
What's his name?
Ask his father.
Cincinnati.
No, come on!
The love of my life seated here
wanted Cynthia when we thought
he was a girl.
However...
They misread the ultrasound.
-Why?
-I only had the first one done.
Do you remember where that was?
-Yes.
-In Sulawao.
-In Sulawesi.
-Sulawesi.
-That one.
It looked like a filthy bike garage.
Unbelievable!
And we never went back.
They took a bullet out of me
during the war in a tractor garage.
-You never told me that, cub.
-For real.
-Where?
-In the ass. Wanna see?
-No...
-No!
Show them your pet, come one, Helsi.
-No.
-Come on! Show them your pet, come on.
-Huh?
-They're family.
OK. Check this out.
I have a new...
No way!
Don't look!
What are you doing?
-It can talk.
-Hey, big man,
want me to train your bear?
I'm good at training animals.
-Did you prefer a girl or a boy, Mónica?
-We didn't care.
We didn't care. You love him or her,
not matter what comes out, right?
It's a boy.
What?
A boy?
It's a boy.
It's a boy!
It's a boy! A boy!
Boy!
It's a boy!
What can I say? I was happy.
You could hear him screaming:
"It's a boy!"
So that's it! From Cynthia...
Cinthy...
Cincy-nati. Cincinnati.
You're insane.
It's pure logic.
He's got a city name.
Like the whole family.
This family.
Cincinnati.
Right?
It's okay, my love. My little boy.
-To him.
-To Cincinnati!
-Well wishes!
-Here, here.
Cheers! To everyone!
Come on.
Guys.
I want to thank you for what you're doing.
In Rio's name and in mine.
-Thank you.
-To Rio!
To Rio! Cheers.
Cheers.
We're doing this for Rio, Tokyo, but...
also for all of us.
Right now, they think they can only win.
Chasing us like animals
and prying us from our holes...
Torturing us. Violating
every human right. Anything goes.
If we hide like rats,
they'll strike again.
One by one.
There's only one way to avoid it.
To face them.
Listen.
In this world...
everything is weighed
on a simple pair of scales:
what you can win
and what you can lose. And right now...
they think they have nothing to lose.
And when you think
you have nothing to lose,
you get stronger.
Well...
we will...
show them...
how much they have...
to lose.
Where's the governor?
Where is he?
Palermo!
We have a problem.
Tokyo.
Take it easy.
-Tokyo.
-Take it easy.
On the count of three, shoot and duck.
One...
Two...
Guns down, you rats!
Ladies and gentlemen,
let me introduce myself.
I'm Palermo
and I'm the one in charge of this robbery.
So, please, aim at my chest.
I'm your most valuable target.
Aim at her!
At her.
Okay...
We have a few seconds
before all the shooting starts,
so let's talk about anatomy.
Human beings have two eyes.
And unlike chameleons,
their eyes are located
in the front of the head and are fixed.
This is clearly a handicap for you
in a shoot-out.
Shoot and your girls will be dead.
I'm talking to you, Gandía.
I know that you go to the firing range
every Sunday,
that you like reading about armaments.
You've been waiting your whole
fucking life for this,
to be a hero.
Let me give you some advice:
think of Marisa,
imagine your son Juanito's angelic face...
and put your fucking gun down very slowly.
Okay.
At that moment, the Professor realized
that this job would be very different
from the one at the Royal Mint.
This one didn't come from his head
and he hadn't had the time
to make it his own.
Had he had a rewind button,
he would have pushed it right then.
But he didn't have one.
Are you okay, Tokyo?
Say something!
Are you okay?
Go check on Palermo!
We fired all our bullets at their vests,
following the Professor's instructions.
-Help Palermo!
-But we were too late.
Wake up! Where's the governor?
We have to get him out of here.
Find a stretcher!
Everything's gone to hell!
His eyes are full of glass!
Shit!
Help me!
Move!
Up against the wall! Against the wall!
Come on! Move!
Come on! Hurry up!
-Come on! Hurry up!
-Move!
-Almost there.
-Careful.
It's okay.
Painkillers!
Calm down.
I'm taking this off very slowly.
Slowly... Easy...
Very good.
Okay. Open your eyes now. Slowly.
Come on.
Very good.
I can't keep them open for too long.
I can't.
Can you see?
I can't see shit. What's happening?
Shit.
Okay. Okay.
How about the light?
As if I were in Maracanã Stadium.
Does that mean anything to you?
You think you're an eye doctor now?
He needs an ophthalmologist!
Call the Professor.
I see the glass.
Okay. Stockholm, first aid kit number 4.
-The surgical one.
-OK.
Hurry up.
-What are you going to do, Tokyo?
-I'm going to remove them.
-Really? How?
-With tweezers.
I wouldn't do that, Tokyo.
Call the Professor
and release three hostages
-for an eye doctor.
-Denver!
-Shut up and leave!
-Okay.
Listen to me, Palermo.
My hand is steadier than
a Swiss watchmaker's.
I'm getting that glass out.
Do you know
why they use lasers for eye surgery?
-Yes.
-For just a tiny detail.
Precision. Eye operations need
to be precise to the micrometer.
Check this out, Denver.
Tokyo wants to use
the same tweezers she uses
to trim her jungle down there.
Come on!
Nonsense!
Say it again.
How was it?
I'm sure
your peach down there is all silky.
Now say, "I will never mention
my colleagues' pussies ever again."
I will never mention
my colleagues' pussies again.
I didn't get that.
-I'll never mention your pussy, bitch.
-Fucking great, Palermo.
At your service.
Okay. We'll deal with my eyes later.
-Denver, on my right.
-What's up?
Give me your arm.
You're my second in command now.
-I'm your damn guide dog now?
-Silence!
-Tokyo!
-What?
We have 14 tons of steel below.
Tell me Nairobi is with Bogotá.
That's right.
Let's go.
Listen. What are you doing?
Are you going to tie us up like dogs?
I'm not.
We're all family here,
in case you need to take a piss.
I'm going to kill you.
Governor, I beg your pardon.
I'll hold onto this for you.
Your attention, please.
We have placed 460 kilos of explosives
on doors, windows,
at every entrance and exit, so in case
anyone tries to escape...
Boom!
They would do so in pieces.
It's not worth it.
We must all stay here together
for a few days, that's right,
but during all this time,
we will
protect you all.
And you will protect us all.
How wonderful!
And now, whenever you want,
you can take the masks off.
Now!
How's that?
How are you?
Now that we can see each other,
let me introduce you to Mr. Bogotá.
He's going to pick four volunteers.
My name is Bogotá
and I came to do the hard part of the job.
We're going to work in
over 65 degrees Celsius.
It's going to feel like
a fucking crematorium.
We'll be doing shifts
of 12, 14, 16 or 24 hours.
As many as you can handle.
Who's in?
Name!
Agustín.
-Agustín Montero.
-Why are you here?
I was...
exchanging currency.
Step forward.
Congratulations,
you're our first volunteer.
Next.
Miguel Talanilla. From Murcia.
-Okay.
-What do you do, Miguel?
I intern at the Operations
and Systems Department.
IT.
-Unsuitable.
-Unsuitable. Next!
Name. Why are you here?
Alfonso.
I have... I had an appointment
at the Public Debt Department.
Step forward. Congratulations,
you're our second volunteer. Next!
Name. Why are you here?
Amanda. I'm the Governor's secretary.
Unsuitable. Come on, next!
Name!
Matías Caño.
Suitable! Step forward.
-No, ma'am.
-Don't "ma'am" me.
You're our next volunteer.
I'm no volunteer.
Okay. Can you see this finger?
This finger points at the volunteers
and it is pointing
at you over and over again.
So, please, step forward
because you're now a volunteer.
Ma'am, I'm no volunteer.
What was your name?
Matías Caño.
What?
Okay, Matías Caño.
You're coming with me right fucking now.
Let's go. Move!
Come on!
Go to the elevator!
Don't move!
Go in!
What was that about?
Are you stupid?
What the fuck was that about?
To seem more credible.
More credible? Do you think
you're fucking Anthony Hopkins now?
I had to act like a hostage, right?
You're joking. From the producers
of "Coming with me right fucking now,"
coming soon to a blacksmith workshop
near you.
I think I did a good job. It went smooth.
I'll slap your face smooth.
Six years!
Six fucking years working with this guy
and six times I've wanted to slam
his head against a wagon.
My dears.
In the next few minutes,
even your balls are at stake.
Sergio!
The CNI has arrived.
Get them bugged.
Colonel Tamayo.
Inspector.
-Time of explosion.
-12:04.
We heard shooting
and they put explosives everywhere.
-How were they detonated?
-We're not sure.
Plastic explosive, RDX. Flawlessly made.
They're bluffing.
It doesn't seem like it.
They're at the front, the roof, inside...
I studied them. They wouldn't blow it up.
Respectfully,
they're capable of anything.
I take a piss and nothing happens.
They're scum.
-Listen to me.
-Please!
Alfonso.
How are you doing?
I'm fucked big time, Luis.
I can't.
I'm sorry. You're in charge.
Don't worry.
Get some rest.
Luis.
Call her.
I sent her to interrogate Aníbal Cortés.
Gentlemen,
we know everyone here.
I'm Colonel Tamayo, Intelligence.
I'm in charge here.
First, I want the queen bitch here.
Get me Alicia Sierra.
Get her on the phone now.
Back to work.
Get me Inspector Sierra right now.
It's her.
Inspector Sierra, you've got
a phone call from Colonel Tamayo.
Talk to me.
Alicia, Tamayo here.
Get something out of him?
Nothing that can help us, Luis.
Send him to his mommy,
to fix him some soup.
He's gone limp
from all the drugs and chats.
Put him on a plane
and come with him to Madrid.
You've got work here.
Let me be part of this, Luis.
Tell me you want me
to get the fucking shepherd
and his sheep out of the bank.
Exactly.
Fuck, yeah...
I'm so happy, my water could break!
I feel uneasy...
in front of all this beauty,
but I've got some pretty unpleasant news.
I've been diagnosed with mom's illness.
How long?
Three years.
At the least.
You know how alarmist doctors are.
In the end, it'll be six.
Or seven.
Like a stray cat's life.
Andrés.
We'll call it all off
and find a treatment abroad.
First, there's no cure.
And, secondly, I enjoy stealing much more.
Do you want to risk spending
the time you have left behind bars?
If a painter told you
he had three years left to live,
would you ask him to stop painting?
Andrés, please...
Look.
Would you have told Michelangelo
to stop sculpting his David?
No. Of course not.
You'd have said: "Forza, Michelangelo!
Continue doing your passion."
A painter? A poet? It's the same thing.
"Gentlemen,
continue creating beauty."
And this job, Sergio,
is an apologia for beauty.
It's our masterpiece.
Sixteen minutes...
and 15 seconds.
That's what it is.
The moment you touch that door,
the vault will be flooded.
Sixteen minutes and 15 seconds.
The time it takes the water
to reach here.
Either we make a hole
and weld the interconnection tube
in that time,
or that's it,
we all end up in prison
for nothing.
For breaking a door.
But that...
that's not...
going to happen to us.
And that's not going to happen
to us because... Bogotá.
What are we?
The fucking best.
No... Not like that.
You can't melt a 14-ton door like that.
What are we?
The fucking best!
That's much better! Grab your lances!
This is not a door.
This is butter.
And you...
You're going to melt it down.
Burnt butter! Take your positions!
Come on, Sergio.
Don't be mean. Imagine it.
Imagine it. You can do it.
Imagine it with me now.
A 14-ton steel door.
And right there,
the best blacksmiths in the world.
Ready?
Tick-tock!
Now!
The moment we touch that door,
water will pour in; 7,500 liters/minute.
Tick-tock!
Come on! Hurry up!
Don't stop!
Once it's full,
you'd be crushed
if you opened that door.
But we're not going to open it.
Exactly.
We're going to penetrate it.
Bring the ram!
Go!
Now!
Tube!
Go! Lead the way!
In the 16 minutes it takes
the vault to fill up, we'll play
Jacques-Yves...
Cousteau.
One, two, three.
Push!
Ready!
Without opening that door,
a welder will go in.
Here.
Okay, we're ready.
Our fate is in your hands.
The oxygen comes first.
-Let me be.
-What are you doing?
-I've got time!
-What the fuck?
Put your oxygen on, Bogotá!
Shit! Why? Why the hell does someone
always have to be the hero?
There's always someone
who has to play the hero!
And right there,
with water rising by the second,
begins the real fantasy
of the new millennium.
Welding a small interconnecting chamber
to both sides.
With water rising by the minute,
it's better than a Bond movie.
Not even James Bond could weld
the antechamber in such a short time.
Exactly!
That's why we'll hire
the best welder in the world.
If the water level is over the welding,
or this welding isn't perfect...
the water will push with such pressure
that we'd need four or five days
to get him out.
So, he'd die!
He'd die!
But what robbery is without risk?
Go!
Don't waste time!
Anyway, brother,
let's not think about that just now.
Come on! Just one more minute!
Just give me one more minute!
Who would imagine that?
Who?
I'm going in.
An interconnecting antechamber.
Just like a bathyscaphe!
So then,
my dearest brother,
there come the bubbles.
You used to love ocean documentaries.
Well, now comes
your most wonderful moment.
As the flotation levels out...
Bogotá!
You're alive!
...you turn around...
see the bubbles...
sparkling bubbles,
because of the gold ingots,
and bursting against the roof.
You'll think you're in the Space Station.
But you aren't.
You're in the vault of the Bank of Spain.
There... floating...
It'd be like entering a sunken galleon
in the middle of the ocean.
Ninety tons of 24K pure gold.
What do you think?
It's the most beautiful thing
I've ever heard.
I told you!
Compay!
Guajira guantanamera
Guantanamera
Do not leave me in the dark
To die like a traitor
I am good and good as I am
I will die facing the sun
Facing the sun, brother.
I want to die on a beach.
When the judge comes to pick up my body,
I want him to say: "That bastard!"
Guajira guantanamera
Let's dance.
Guantanamera
Guajira guantanamera
Dance with me.
My babies...
Look what I brought.
Look at these little earrings I've found.
Would you look at that?
Golden! Sweet gold!
That's right!